Emmanuel Makokha jmakoks@gmail.com +254708953535

January 12th, 2023

The Human Resource Manager ALX Tech.

Application for the Position of Intern Developer Assistant at ALX

Dear sir/madam,

I am excited to apply for the Intern Developer Assistant position I found on Twitter. I understand that you are actively recruiting professionals in the technology related field. I believe my skills will provide a significant advantage to the ALX team and its users.

While I was working as an intern in Jomo Kenyatta University, I was galvanized in creating a program that would store students' data in an efficient way and the staff would access information even in a remote location. Besides, I am passionate about technology and computer innovation. I opted to enroll for Full Stack Software Engineering course at African Leadership Experience. The Bachelor in Technical and Applied Physics developed a pathway to break big problems into small manageable ones through extensive research and experiments.

Solving people's problem by writing efficient programs is always a top priority. Therefore, having a solid knowledge in computer networking, Linux and Windows operating systems, C programming, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Python, MySQL, data structures and algorithms is just the beginning. Lately, I have created projects such as printf, Monty, and simple shell.

Thank you for your time and considerations. I'm looking forward to learning more details about the position of Intern Developer Assistant position and integration process into your company to my continued success. Also, I am excited for the opportunity to be part of ALX Tech. My proven skills and experience are a winning combination for the company's growth.

Sincerely, Emmanuel Makokha.

EMMANUEL MAMAI MAKOKHA

Nairobi | +254 708953535 | <u>jmakoks@gmail.com</u> | <u>https://github.com/MamaiTheCoder</u> www.linkedin.com/in/mamaithecoder

Full Stack Software Developer

Web-Based Application Designer – Object-oriented programmer – Management of database

Possess interpersonal skills to collaborate, communicate, think critically, empathize, and lead • Have a growth mindset and learn in mentorship, coaching, on-the-job learning with GitHub, and search engines • Can interface in remote and team setting • Possess technical knowledge of full stack software development • Manage time effectively to track progress, measure productivity, and achieve a goal setting • Business insight in collecting and working on user feedback, and understanding the end-user personas in software and web development applications • Deploy requirement analysis in software design and do testing, prototyping, and design analysis

Education

Full Stack Software Engineer – Africa Leadership Experience

Bachelor of Technology (Technical & Applied Physics) – T. U. K.

Certificate of Computer Applications – Legacy College

Aug 2022 – Present May 2012 – 2017

June 2013 - Sept 2013

Projects

Web Development

- Problem recommender: recommend problems for coding practice in CLI tool.
- printf project in C.
- Simple shell
- Monty Interpreter.

Achievements

- Member to the Information Technology team in JKUAT.
- Successfully created a fully responsive web design that could respond to different screen sizes.
- Developed an algorithm that perform search tasks in thousands of data within 5 seconds
- Created a database in JKUAT that had all students record in a click of a button.

Professional Experience

Statistician – JKUAT Feb 2021 – Feb 2022

- Collecting, analyzing, and interpreting data of self-sponsored students.
- Finding trends, dependent variables and independent variables in the data.
- Design the process of data collection to come up with reliable data.
- Assisting in the decision making.
- Researching on the strategies to improve on learning in the institution and maintain the consistency of students to be enrolled.
- Writing reports on the situation of the institution.
- Present data in charts and tables.
- Using different statistical software in analysis data including statistical packaging for the social sciences, Rstudio, and Scilab.

Technical software developer

2018 - 2020

- ❖ Coding in JavaScript, C++, and Python programming languages.
- Manage projects using pert chart.

Intern at Communications Authority of Kenya

Feb 2016 - May 2016

- Inspection of frequency interference using the Q-voice machine.
- Guidance of clients on the process of the license application and advising them accordingly.
- Installation of radio frequency.
- Performance of simple laboratory tests on small equipment like set-top boxes.
- Tracking of the applicants' license application progress and advising them on the necessary steps to be taken

Technical Proficiency

- ❖ Languages: Bash, C/C++, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Frameworks: Git and GitHub, React and React Native, SQL, Node.js, Django

Skill Summary

Operating Systems • UI Toolkits and Frameworks • Computer Architecture • Team Building • Critical thinking • Consumer Experiences • Design Concepts and ERDs • Design Reviews • Flowcharts and Pseudocode • Growth mindset • Source code • Data Structures and Algorithms • Software Testing • Code Debugging and Troubleshooting.

Referees

Mrs. Morine Kerubo, Sec, JKUAT. Prof. J. Odote – Director, SSPI. Mrs. M. Njiraini – Manager, C. A. K

njiraini@ca.go.ke

Tel: 0722151480 Tel: 0722735720

Tel: 0722753743